Chris Asmanis

Toronto, ON chrisasmanis@gmail.com

+1 (437) 345-6219 linkedin.com/in/chrisasmanis/

CIVIL / TRANSPORTATION ENGINEER

A passionate civil engineer from Melbourne, Australia, currently in my 4th year of experience in the traffic and transport industry. Recently arrived in Toronto with a two-year open work permit, aiming to gain quality international experience in the transport industry. Committed to efficiently preparing high quality work and delivering on client expectations and deadlines.

Highly organized with the ability to learn quickly and the desire to continually expand capabilities. Valuable interpersonal and communication skills are what I believe assist me in being successful as a consultant. Currently seeking a new and challenging transportation engineering role, where I will have the opportunity to grow and be part of a high-achieving team with the prospect of working on a diverse range of projects.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Traffic and Transport Engineer SALT3, Melbourne, Australia Sep 2017 – Present (SALT3 is an engineering consultancy, specializing in traffic, transport and waste engineering)

- Preparation of traffic engineering technical reports, assessments and consultant advice to assist with town planning applications;
- Research and development of transport and movement strategies, most notably the Warburton Transport and Movement Strategy which encourages sustainable modes of transport and protecting vulnerable road users;
- Car park and intersection layout design and refinement using AutoCAD and AutoTurn, providing clients with high-quality, efficient and cost-effective design solutions;
- Preparation of Traffic Management Plans (TMPs) for small and large worksites, ensuring minimal disruption to the surrounding road network;
- Writing detailed fee proposals and completing tender documentation, assisting the company to win work and enhance the company's presence within the industry; and
- Regular attendance at industry networking and business development events.

Project Engineer Yarra City Council, Melbourne, Australia Jan 2016 – Sep 2017 (The City of Yarra is an inner-city municipality, home to arterial roads experiencing Melbourne's highest daily volumes of traffic)

- Initially worked at Yarra as a Student Engineer as part of an Industry Based Learning program, before staying onboard as a Project Engineer after the six-month program ended;
- Project managed the 2016/17 federally funded Black Spot Program, involving design and delivery of \$2million worth of capital works projects to increase safety for all road users around Yarra;
- Assumed a leading role in delivery of the City's annual Local Area Traffic Management (LATM) program, working with civil works contractors to deliver all projects on time and on (or under) budget;
- · Preparation of technical reports to obtain external funding for road safety improvement projects; and
- Gained certification as a VicRoads accredited Road Safety Auditor.

Chris Asmanis Page 2

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Bachelor of Civil Engineering (Honours), Swinburne University, Melbourne 2013 - 2017 Modules included: Project management, transport engineering and management, Computer Aided Design (CAD), building design, engineering management, international construction and cost engineering.

Main project: Final year research project investigated the potential to restore timber bridges using Fibre Reinforced Polymer (FRP) materials and the benefits this could reap for the asset owner (road authority). Received an overall grade of 94/100 for the project.

This course had a strong focus on team work and enhancing students' ability to prepare concise and
meaningful technical reports. Whilst all the relevant technical skills were covered, Swinburne had an
additional focus of placing students into practical situations on real life projects, to gain a detailed
understanding of industry expectations.

Advanced Diploma of Civil Engineering, Swinburne University, Melbourne 2011 - 2012

Modules included: Engineering principles, report preparation, surveying, Computer Aided Design (CAD), Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint) specific courses and sustainability in engineering.

The Advanced Diploma course had a "hands on" approach, teaching engineering principles through
means of demonstration and practical activities. A strong emphasis was placed on competence with
AutoCAD and Microsoft Office software packages, which has proven invaluable within the workplace.

Courses and Memberships:

- VicRoads Road Safety Engineering Workshop, to become a state accredited Road Safety Auditor.
- Member of the Australian Institute of Traffic Planning and Management (AITPM).

Software skills:

- Advanced level of AutoCAD proficiency
- AutoTurn software for AutoCAD
- Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint)
- SIDRA intersection analysis

 Desire to gain proficiency with alternative software packages such as Synchro/SimTraffic and Bentley Microstation, Projectwise, InRoads, etc.

Other:

- Hold a valid Ontario G-class drivers license.
- Very interested in attaining bilingual proficiency in French.